翻译/佩佩家的拖拉机 Middy Season Tacitee Riverpond Adriana J
审校/佩佩家的拖拉机 Ker   后期/大西
注意左边
On your left.
呵呵 注意左边 我知道了
Uh-huh. On my left. Got it.
不要再说了 告诉我你没准备说
Don't say it. Don't you say it.
- 注意左边   - 干嘛呀
- On your left.   - Come on!
要叫医生吗
Need a medic?
给我换套新肺吧
I need a new set of lungs.
哥们儿 你刚刚在30分钟里跑了13公里啊
Dude, you just ran, like, 13 miles in 30 minutes.
大概我起跑晚了
Guess I got a late start.
真的？你真该为自己感到羞耻
Really? You should be ashamed of yourself.
快去再跑一圈
You should take another lap.
你刚刚跑完了对吧？ 我就当你跑完一圈了
Did you just take it?  I assume you just took it.
你是哪个部队的
What unit you with?
58空降救援师
58th Pararescue.
现在在退伍军人事务部上班
But now I'm working down at the VA.
VA-United States Department of Veterans Affairs 美国退伍军人事务部
- 我叫山姆·威尔逊   - 史蒂夫·罗杰斯
- Sam Wilson.   - Steve Rogers.
我想起你是谁了
I kind of put that together.
你被解冻之后 一定被现代世界吓到了吧
Must have freaked you out, coming home after the whole defrosting thing.
我花了不少时间去适应这个世界
It takes some getting used to.
很高兴见到你 山姆
It's good to meet you, Sam.
是适应床花了你不少时间吧
It's your bed, right?
什么
What's that?
你的床太软了
Your bed, it's too soft.
过去我打仗的时候都睡在地上
When I was over there, I'd sleep on the ground,
常常拿石头当枕头 像个穴居人
use rock for pillows, like a caveman.
现在回家了 睡在床上 感觉像是...
Now I'm home, lying in my bed, and it's like...
睡在棉花糖上一样
Lying on a marshmallow.
感觉会一直陷进地板里
Feel like I'm gonna sink right to the floor.
在部队呆了多久
How long?
被外派执行了两次任务
Two tours.
你一定很怀念那些美好时光吧
You must miss the good old days, huh?
现在过得也都挺好的
Well, things aren't so bad.
食物要好得多 以前什么都是煮着吃
Food's a lot better.  We used to boil everything.
没有小儿麻痹症 这很好
No polio is good.
互联网 功能强大
Internet, so helpful.
我在网上看了很多东西 努力跟上时代
I've been reading that a lot, trying to catch up.
听听马文·盖伊1972年的原声带专辑 "Trouble Man"
Marvin Gaye, 1972, <i>Trouble Man</i> soundtrack.
马文·盖伊 美国摩城唱片著名黑人歌手 有"摩城王子"之称
你要补的东西都在这张专辑里面了
Everything you missed jammed into one album.
我要把这个记在备忘录上
I'll put it on the list.
有任务 立即动身 路边见
好了 山姆 该去工作了 谢谢你陪我跑步
All right, Sam, duty calls.  Thanks for the run.
如果你把那称为跑步的话
If that's what you want to call running.
哦 评价这么低
Oh, that's how it is?
- 就是这么低   - 好吧
- Oh, that's how it is.   - Okay.
如果你哪天来退伍军人部 事先告诉我一声
Any time you want to stop by the VA, make me look awesome
让我能在前台小姐面前显摆显摆
in front of the girl at the front desk, just let me know.
我会记住的
I'll keep it in mind.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, fellas.
知道怎么去史密森尼学会吗
Either one of you know where the Smithsonian is?
Smithsonian 史密森尼学会 成立于1846年华盛顿
我要去接个活化石
I'm here to pick up a fossil.
真会开玩笑
That's hilarious.
- 你好    - 嘿
- How you doing?   - Hey.
不能去哪儿都用跑的吧
Can't run everywhere.
可不是吗
No, you can't.
印度洋
纬度 16N 55' 12.06"    经度 72N 56' 7.09"
目标是移动卫星发射台
Target is a mobile satellite launch platform,
利莫里亚之星
the <i>Lemurian Star.</i>
海盗劫持的时候他们正在发射最后一颗卫星
They were sending up their last payload when pirates took them,
93分钟前
93 minutes ago.
- 要多少赎金   - 1.5亿美金
- Any demands?   - Billion and a half.
- 这么夸张   - 因为是神盾局的船
- Why so steep?   - Because it's S.H.I.E.L.D.'s.
所以那船不是偏离航向 是非法入侵
So it's not off-course. It's trespassing.
我肯定 这么做一定有原因
I'm sure they have a good reason.
你知道吗 我讨厌老帮弗瑞擦屁股
Yeah, I'm getting a little tired of being Fury's janitor.
放轻松 这事没那么麻烦
Relax. It's not that complicated.
海盗有多少
How many pirates?
25个 以这个家伙为首的顶级雇佣兵
25. Top mercs led by this guy.
乔治·巴托克 前法国驻外安全行动部队指挥官
Georges Batroc. Ex-DGSE, Action Division.
国际刑警头号通缉犯
He's at the top of Interpol's Red Notice.
在法国警方追捕他之前执行过36个刺杀任务
Before the French demobilised him, he had 36 kill missions.
这家伙以凶狠残忍出名
This guy's got a rep for maximum casualties.
人质呢
Hostages?
大部分都是技术人员 只有一个官员 贾斯帕·希特维尔
Oh, mostly techs. One officer. Jasper Sitwell.
人质都关在厨房里
They're in the galley.
希特维尔去发射台干嘛
What's Sitwell doing on a launch ship?
这样 我去甲板上进行地毯式搜索 寻找巴托克
All right, I'm gonna sweep the deck and find Batroc.
娜塔莎 你关掉发动机 然后等待下一步的指示
Nat, you kill the engines and wait for instructions.
朗姆洛 你去船尾搜寻
Rumlow, you sweep aft, find the hostages,
找到人质 带他们上救生艇 开始行动
get them to the life-pods, get them out. Let's move.
特战队 一切听从罗杰斯队长指挥 整装出发
S.T.R.I.K.E., you heard the Cap. Gear up.
7频道通话确认
Secure channel seven.
7频道确认
Seven secure.
你礼拜六晚上玩什么啦
Did you do anything fun Saturday night?
以前跟我一起混的人都死光了
Well, all the guys from my barbershop quartet are dead,
所以 没玩什么
so, no, not really.
我们到达指定区域了 队长
<i>Coming up on the drop zone, Cap.</i>
你要是约统计部的克里斯汀的话 她可能会同意
You know, if you ask Kristen out, from Statistics, she'd probably say yes.
所以我没约她
That's why I don't ask.
太害羞还是太害怕
Too shy, or too scared?
是太忙了
Too busy!
他带降落伞了吗
Was he wearing a parachute?
没
No.
他没带
No, he wasn't.
别动
Don't move.
谢谢
Thanks.
不谢 你好像没我不行啊
Yeah. You seemed pretty helpless without me.
住你对面的女护士可以考虑看看
What about the nurse that lives across the hall from you?
她好像还不错哟
She seems kind of nice.
拿下轮机舱再帮我找女朋友
Secure the engine room, then find me a date.
我能一心多用
I'm multi-tasking.
我告诉过巴托克
I told Batroc...
如果我们想要神盾局乖乖交赎金
If we want to make S.H.I.E.L.D. pay us...
现在就要杀几个人给他们点压力
...start sending them bodies now!
我可以杀一个人
I have a bullet for someone...
想吃子弹吗
You want a bullet in your head?
腿挪开 你想脑袋上挨一枪吗
Move that foot - you want a bullet in the head?
我不喜欢等
I don't like waiting.
联系杜兰德
Coll Durand.
我希望赎金一到我们的船就可以安全离开
I want this ship ready to move when the ransom comes.
遵命 巴托克
Yes, Batroc.
开船
Start the engines.
好吧
Okay.
嘿 水手
Hey, sailor.
闭嘴
Shut up.
想干嘛 想逞英雄
You want to be a hero? Is that it?
不行了 我等不下去了
All right, I've waited long enough...
去找巴托克
Find Batroc...
要是两分钟内再没动静
If I don't hear anything in two minutes...
我就要开始杀人了
...I start killing them!
我去找他
I'll find him.
只等两分钟
Two minutes.
神盾局的无线电静默 巴托克
Radio silence from S.H.I.E.L.D., Batroc...
目标锁定
Targets acquired.
特战队就位
S.T.R.I.K.E. in position.
娜塔莎 你那边的情况怎么样
Natasha, what's your status?
回话 娜塔莎
<i>Status, Natasha.</i>
等一下
Hang on!
轮机舱拿下
Engine room secure.
时间到了
Time is up.
谁想第一个死
Who dies first...?
你!
You!
把那个女的带出来
Take the girl.
听我口令
On my mark.
三
<i>Three...</i>
二...一
<i>Two... One.</i>
我告诉过你 神盾局从不谈判
I told you, S.H.I.E.L.D. doesn't negotiate.
有人吗
Hello?
巴托克  无人回应
Batroc, The line just went dead.
和他们失去联系了
I've lost contact with them...
人质已在撤离的路上了
Hostages en route to extraction.
诺曼诺夫没到达集合点 队长
Romanoff missed the rendezvous point, Cap.
敌人还在行动
Hostiles are still in play.
娜塔莎 巴托克逃跑了
Natasha, Batroc's on the move.
你回去找朗姆洛汇合 同时确保人质安全
Circle back to Rumlow and protect the hostages.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
你不会就靠那个盾牌吧
I thought you were more than just a shield...
走着瞧
Let's see.
哦 太尴尬了
Well, this is awkward.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
备份硬盘数据
Backing up the hard drive.
这可是个好习惯
It's a good habit to get into.
朗姆洛需要你的支援
Rumlow needed your help.
你到底在这干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
你在保存神盾局的情报
You're saving S.H.I.E.L.D. intel.
能存多少就存多少
Whatever I can get my hands on.
我们是来解救人质的
Our mission is to rescue hostages.
不 那是你的任务
No, that's your mission,
你完成的很漂亮
and you've done it beautifully.
你把整个行动陷于危险之中
You just jeopardised this whole operation.
你也太小题大做了
I think that's a overstating thing.
好吧
Okay.
这次是我的错
That one's on me.
那还用说
You're damn right.
三曲翼大楼
神盾局总部
纬度 38N 53' 33.78   经度 77S 3'38.91
你骗人骗惯了 不想骗也难是吧
You just can't stop yourself from lying, can you?
我没骗你
I didn't lie.
诺曼诺夫特工跟你的任务不同
Agent Romanoff had a different mission than yours.
你觉得你没有义务跟我们说一下吗
Which you didn't feel obliged to share.
没什么事情是我有义务做的
I'm not obliged to do anything.
那些人质可能会死的 尼克
Those hostages could have died, Nick.
所以我派出了历史上最伟大的战士 确保这种事不会发生
I sent the greatest soldier in history to make sure that didn't happen.
战士们互相信任 这样才能称之为军队
Soldiers trust each other. That's what makes it an army.
否则就是一帮开枪乱跑的乌合之众
Not a bunch of guys running around shooting guns.
上次我相信了别人 结果我瞎了一只眼
Last time I trusted someone, I lost an eye.
听着 我不会让你做任何 你觉得不习惯的事
Look, I didn't want you doing anything you weren't comfortable with.
诺曼诺夫特工已经习惯了各种任务
Agent Romanoff is comfortable with everything.
如果我领导的人都带着自己的任务
I can't lead a mission
那我就没办法带队
when the people I'm leading have missions of their own.
这叫分割管理
It's called compartmentalisation.
没人知道全部的的秘密 也就不会有人泄密
Nobody spills the secrets, because nobody knows them all.
但是你知道全部秘密
Except you.
你对我有些误解
You're wrong about me.
我是会分享的
I do share.
我人很好的
I'm nice like that.
去洞察计划室
Insight bay.
罗杰斯队长无权访问
<i>Captain Rogers does not have</i>
洞察计划项目
<i>clearance for Project Insight.</i>
局长修改信息 尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞
Director override. Fury, Nicholas J.
确认修改
<i>Confirmed.</i>
电梯里面以前还会放放音乐
You know, they used to play music.
我知道
Yeah.
我爷爷管理电梯管理了40年
My grandfather operated one of these things for 40 years.
他管理的电梯在一栋高级大楼里
Granddad worked in a nice building.
能赚不少小费
Got good tips.
他每晚步行回家 午餐袋里面就装着一卷一卷的小费
He'd walk home every night, a roll of ones stuffed in his lunch bag.
他向人家问好
He'd say, "Hi."
别人也向他问好
People would say, "Hi" back.
时间流逝 街坊邻里没那么友善了
Time went on, the neighbourhood got rougher.
他再向别人问好
He'd say, "Hi."
人家说走你的路吧
They'd say, "Keep on steppin'."
我爷爷把午餐袋抓得越来越紧
Granddad got to gripping that lunch bag a little tighter.
他从来没被抢过吗
Did he ever get mugged?
每个星期都有小混混问他包里面装的是什么
Every week some punk would say, "What's in the bag?"
你爷爷怎么做的
What would he do?
他会打开包给他们看
He'd show them.
一沓一块钱 还有一把上了膛的22 Mag气枪
Bunch of crumpled ones, and a loaded .22 Magnum.
.22 Winchester Magnum Rimfire原产美国
我爷爷与人为善
Yeah, Granddad loved people.
但他并不会完全信任他们
But he didn't trust them very much.
对 我知道
Yeah, I know.
这个要比.22大一点
They're a little bit bigger than a .22.
这是洞察计划
This is Project Insight.
三架最新一代天空母舰
Three next-generation helicarriers
与目标锁定卫星网络同步
synced to a network of targeting satellites.
用利莫里亚之星发射的
Launched from the <i>Lemurian Star.</i>
一旦它们被送上天 就无需再降落了
Once we get them in the air, they never need to come down.
多亏了我们的新型反重力引擎让它们能进行持续的亚轨道飞行
Continuous sub-orbital flight, courtesy of our new repulsor engines.
斯塔克的杰作
Stark?
他近距离观察了我们的老式
He had a few suggestions
涡轮机之后 给了一些建议
once he got an up-close look at our old turbines.
这些新型远程精准机炮
These new long-range precision guns
可以一分钟消灭上千个敌人
can eliminate 1,000 hostiles a minute.
在恐怖分子走出掩蔽坑之前 卫星就能够识别出他们的DNA
The satellites can read a terrorist's DNA before he steps outside his spider hole.
我们就可以消灭很多潜在威胁 防患于未然
We're gonna neutralise a lot of threats before they even happen.
不是先有罪 再有罚吗
Thought the punishment usually came after the crime.
我们可等不起
We can't afford to wait that long.
“我们”指的是
Who's "we"?
纽约事件之后 我说服世界安全理事会
After New York, I convinced the World Security Council
要彻底提高威胁分析技术
we needed a quantum surge in threat analysis.
至少这次我们能未雨绸缪了
For once, we're way ahead of the curve.
拿着枪对着地球上的每个人 还号称保护？
By holding a gun to everyone on Earth and calling it protection.
我看了战略科研署的档案
You know, I read those SSR files.
你们这些所谓的最伟大的一代
"Greatest Generation"?
也干过一些不光彩的事
You guys did some nasty stuff.
是的 我们妥协了
Yeah, we compromised.
有些事让我们良心不安 睡不着觉
Sometimes in ways that made us not sleep so well.
但是我们这么做是为了全人类的自由
But we did it so that people could be free.
这可不是自由 这是恐惧
This isn't freedom. This is fear.
神盾局看待世界的眼光是现实的 不是理想化的
S.H.I.E.L.D. takes the world as it is, not as we'd like it to be.
你也应该识点儿时务了 别老唱反调 队长
And it's getting damn near past time for you to get with that Programme, Cap.
你就别指望了
Don't hold your breath.
欢迎来到史密森尼博物馆
<i>Welcome to the Smithsonian.</i>
游客问询处位于二楼
<i>Visitor information booths are available on the second level.</i>
他是国家的象征
<i>A symbol to the nation.</i>
世界的英雄
<i>A hero to the world.</i>
美国队长的故事是一个关于光荣 勇敢与牺牲的故事
<i>The story of Captain America is one of Honour, bravery and sacrifice.</i>
史蒂夫·罗杰斯由于身体孱弱而被拒绝入伍
<i>Denied enlistment due to poor health,</i>
却被美国军事战争史上
<i>Steven Rogers was chosen for a Programme</i>
一个独特的项目选中
<i>unique in the annals of American warfare.</i>
这个项目会让他成为世界第一位超级战士
<i>One that would transform him into the world's first Super-Soldier.</i>
在这珍贵镜头中
<i>In this rare footage,</i>
大家最爱的勇士 美国队长
<i>everyone's favourite war hero, Captain America...</i>
经过战火的洗礼
<i>Battle tested,</i>
美国队长
<i>Captain America</i>
和他的咆哮突击队证明了自己的价值
<i>and his Howling Commandos quickly earned their stripes.</i>
他们的任务是
<i>Their mission:</i>
粉碎纳粹的疯狂科研部队 九头蛇
<i>taking down HYDRA, the Nazi rogue science division.</i>
巴基·巴恩斯与史蒂芬·罗杰斯
<i>Best friends since childhood,</i>
自幼就是最好的朋友 形影不离
<i>Bucky Barnes and Steven Rogers were inseparable</i>
无论是在校园里 还是在战场上
<i>on both schoolyard and battlefield.</i>
巴恩斯是咆哮突击队中唯一一个
<i>Barnes is the only Howling Commando to give his life</i>
为国捐躯的队员
<i>in service of his country.</i>
那是一个艰苦的冬天
<i>That was a difficult winter.</i>
暴风雪把一半的部队困在了德军防线里
<i>A blizzard had trapped half our battalion behind the German line.</i>
史蒂夫 罗杰斯队长
<i>Steve, Captain Rogers,</i>
他单枪匹马冲出了九头蛇的封锁线
<i>he fought his way through a HYDRA blockade</i>
这条封锁线我们的盟军几个月都无法突破
<i>that had pinned our allies down for months.</i>
他挽救了一千多人的生命
<i>He saved over 1,000 men.</i>
包括那个
<i>Including the man who would...</i>
后来成为我丈夫的人
<i>Who would become my husband, as it turned out.</i>
即使在史蒂夫牺牲后 他也仍然影响着我的人生
<i>Even after he died, Steve was still changing my life.</i>
你应该为自己感到骄傲 佩吉
You should be proud of yourself, Peggy.
我的人生很圆满
I have lived a life.
唯一的遗憾是你没能为自己而活
My only regret is that you didn't get to live yours.
怎么了
What is it?
在我印象中 我一直想做我认为正确的事
For as long as I can remember, I just wanted to do what was right.
可我现在搞不清到底什么才是正确的了
I guess I'm not quite sure what that is any more.
我曾以为我会重新全心全意投入到执行命令
And I thought I could throw myself back in and follow orders.
为国效力的事业中
Serve.
现在不一样了
It's just not the same.
你总是这么出人意料
You're always so dramatic.
听着 你拯救了世界
Look, you saved the world.
我们却...又搞得一团糟
We rather mucked it up.
并不是这样
You didn't.
我留在神盾局多半是因为是它是你帮忙建立的
Knowing that you helped found S.H.I.E.L.D. is half the reason I stay.
世界已经变了 我们都回不到过去
The world has changed, and none of us can go back.
我们能做的便是尽所能做到最好
All we can do is our best.
有时我们能做的最好的事就是重新开始
And sometimes the best that we can do is to start over.
佩吉
Peggy.
史蒂夫
Steve.
恩
Yeah?
你还活着
You're alive.
你终于回来了
You came back.
是啊 佩吉
Yeah, Peggy.
这么久才回来
It's been so long.
太久了
So long.
我是不会扔下我的女朋友不管的
Well, I couldn't leave my best girl.
她还欠我一支舞呢
Not when she owes me a dance.
封闭办公室
Secure office.
打开利莫里亚之星的发射文件
Open <i>Lemurian Star's</i> satellite launch file.
拒绝访问
<i>Access denied.</i>
运行解密文件
Run decryption.
解密失败
<i>Decryption failed.</i>
局长改写 尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞
Director override. Fury, Nicholas J.
拒绝改写 所有文件已封存
<i>Override denied. All files sealed.</i>
谁授权的
On whose authority?
尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞
<i>Fury, Nicholas J.</i>
世界安全理事会
World Security Council.
确认
<i>Confirmed.</i>
如果尼克·弗瑞认为能叫那些奇装异服的暴徒
<i>If Nick Fury thinks he can get his costumed thugs</i>
和特战队帮他收拾烂摊子
<i>and S.T.R.I.K.E. commandos to mop up his mess, he's sadly mistaken.</i>
那他就错了
This failure is unacceptable.
考虑到此次袭击发生在
Considering this attack took place
距离我国领海一英里的地方
one mile from my country's sovereign waters,
就更是不能接受了 我要求立即召开听证会
it's a bit more than that. I move for immediate hearing.
我们不需要听证会 我们需要行动
We don't need hearings, we need action.
监督神盾局是理事会的职责
It's this Council's duty to oversee S.H.I.E.L.D.
这次侵害事件引发了很多严重的问题
A breach like this raises serious questions.
一群法国海盗
Like how the hell did a French pirate
到底是怎么在光天化日之下劫持一艘隐蔽的神盾局船只
manage to hijack a covert S.H.I.E.L.D. vessel in broad daylight?
理事先生 准确的说他是阿尔及利亚人
For the record, Councilman, he's Algerian.
如果有用的话 我可以画张地图
I can draw a map if it'd help.
我十分欣赏您的智慧  皮尔斯部长
I appreciate your wit, Secretary Pierce.
但是理事会很重视国际海盗问题
But this Council takes things like international piracy fairly seriously.
是吗 我不重视
Really? I don't.
我不在乎一艘船 我关心大局
I don't care about one boat, I care about the fleet.
如果每次有人把我们推上风口浪尖
If this Council is going to fall to rancour
理事会都要出来指责一番
every time someone pushes us on the playing field,
看来需要有人来监督理事会了
maybe we need someone to oversee us.
部长先生 没有人说要...
Mr Secretary, nobody is suggesting...
失陪
Excuse me.
又有麻烦了 部长先生？
More trouble, Mr Secretary?
那取决于你怎么看了
Depends on your definition.
我们在一栋楼里 有了劫持事件你才来看看我
I work 40 floors away and it takes a hijacking for you to visit?
发生核战争我也会来的
A nuclear war would do it, too.
在忙吗？
You busy in there?
专项拨款什么都能搞定
Nothing some earmarks can't fix.
我来请你帮个忙
I'm here to ask a favour.
我想请你组织一次投票
I want you to call for a vote.
洞察计划必须要推迟
Project Insight has to be delayed.
尼克 这可不是个忙
Nick, that's not a favour,
这得开听证会 要开很久
that's a sub-committee hearing. A long one.
（洞察计划）可能没大碍 也许根本没有问题
It could be nothing. It probably is nothing.
我只是需要时间来确定它一切完好
I just need time to make sure it's nothing.
如果有呢？
But if it's something?
那我们都要庆幸那些天空母舰没有被送上天
Then we'll both be damn glad those helicarriers aren't in the air.
好吧
Fine.
但是你必须让钢铁侠去我侄子的生日派对
But you got to get Iron Man to stop by my niece's birthday party.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
不是只是晃一下 要融入其中
And not just a flyby. He's got to mingle.
问题是
The thing is,
我觉得它变得更糟了
I think it's getting worse.
上个星期我被警察拦住
A cop pulled me over last week.
他怀疑我酒驾
He thought I was drunk.
因为我急转弯 绕过了一个塑料袋
I swerved to miss a plastic bag.
我以为那是炸弹
I thought it was an IED.
你们在那里留下一些东西
Some stuff you leave there.
也带回一些东西
Other stuff you bring back.
我们要做的是弄明白应该如何处理它们
It's our job to figure out how to carry it.
是把他们放进大箱子里 还是放进小钱包里
Is it gonna be in a big suitcase, or in a little man-purse?
这取决于你自己
It's up to you.
- 下周见   - 好的
- I'll see you next week.   - Definitely.
看啊 这是谁 跑步男
Look who it is, the running man.
我赶上了最后几分钟 挺沉重的
Caught the last few minutes. It's pretty intense.
是啊 兄弟 我们总有些相同的问题
Yeah, brother, we all got the same problems.
愧疚
Guilt,
悔恨
regret.
你失去过什么人吗
You lose someone?
我的搭档 莱利
My wingman, Riley.
在执行一次夜间飞行任务时
Flying a night mission.
标准的伞降救援
Standard PJ rescue Op.
我们以前不知道做过多少次了
Nothing we hadn't done 1,000 times before.
一枚火箭弹把莱利打下来
Until an RPG knocked Riley's dumb ass out of the sky.
我什么都做不了
Nothing I could do.
只能眼睁睁的看着
It's like I was up there just to watch.
- 我很遗憾   - 那之后
- I'm sorry.   - After that,
我痛苦了很久 思考我留在那的理由
I had a really hard time finding a reason for being over there, you know?
但你现在很开心吧 回归现实世界
But you're happy now, back in the world?
给我下命令的人在这里几乎为零
The number of people giving me orders is down to about zero.
所以 是的
So, hell yeah.
你有没有想过退役
Are you thinking about getting out?
没有
No.
我不知道
I don't know.
说实话 我不知道我要是退役了 我能干什么
To be honest, I don't know what I would do with myself if I did.
终极格斗赛
Ultimate fighting?
我刚才突然想到的
Just a great idea off the top of my head.
说真的 无论你想做什么都行
Seriously, you could do whatever you want to do.
什么能让你开心
What makes you happy?
我不知道
I don't know.
启动通信加密协议
<i>Activating communications encryption protocol.</i>
打开安全线路0405
Open secure line 0405.
确认
<i>Confirmed.</i>
我是希尔
<i>This is Hill.</i>
我需要你来趟华盛顿
I need you here in D.C.
现在是深影状态
Deep shadow conditions.
给我四小时
<i>Give me four hours.</i>
你有三小时 完毕
You have three. Over.
要看我的驾照吗
Want to see my lease?
检测到骨折
<i>Fracture detected.</i>
建议麻醉注射
<i>Recommend anaesthetic injection.</i>
华盛顿调配显示该区域无警力
<i>D.C. Metro Police dispatch shows no units in this area.</i>
带我离开这鬼地方
Get me out of here.
推进系统下线
<i>Propulsion systems offline.</i>
那就赶快重启啊
Then reboot, damn it!
警告 车窗完整度损坏
<i>Warning. Window integrity compromised.</i>
你确定
You think?
要多久能连上推进系统
How long to propulsion?
计算中
<i>Calculating.</i>
车窗完整度31% 采取应对措施
<i>Window integrity 31 %. Deploying countermeasures.</i>
先别执行
Hold that order!
车窗完整度19%
<i>Window integrity 19%.</i>
建议采取攻击性措施
<i>Offensive measures advised.</i>
等等
Wait!
车窗完整度1%
<i>Window integrity 1%.</i>
攻击
Now!
推进系统现已连接
<i>Propulsion systems now online.</i>
立即全速前进
Full acceleration! Now!
启动垂直起飞程序
Initiate vertical takeoff!
飞行系统已损坏
<i>Flight systems damaged.</i>
那就启动导航摄像头
Then activate guidance cameras!
我要手动驾驶
Give me the wheel!
联系希尔特工
Get me Agent Hill.
通讯阵列损坏
<i>Communications array damaged.</i>
有什么是没坏的吗
Well, what's not damaged?
空调系统目前正常运转
<i>Air conditioning is fully operational.</i>
前方交通管制
<i>Traffic ahead.</i>
给我另外一条路线
Give me an alternate route.
罗斯福大桥有交通警报
<i>Traffic alert on Roosevelt Bridge.</i>
所有车辆停止前进
<i>All vehicles stopped.</i>
距离我们三个街区的十七号大道畅通
<i>17th Avenue clear in three blocks, directly ahead.</i>
接近十字路口
<i>Warning. Approaching intersection.</i>
别带我走大路
Get me off the grid!
计算前往安全地点的路线
<i>Calculating route to secure location.</i>
太棒了 太好了
So sweet. That is so nice.
嘿
Hi.
我得挂电话了
I got to go, though.
好的 拜拜
Okay. Bye.
我姑妈 她总是失眠
My aunt, she's kind of an insomniac.
嘿，如果你愿意...
Hey, if you want...
如果你愿意的话 你可以用我的洗衣机
If you want, you're welcome to use my machine.
大概比地下室的要便宜一些
Might be cheaper than the one in the basement.
噢 真的吗 多少钱
Oh, yeah? What's it cost?
一杯咖啡吧
A cup of coffee?
谢谢 但是
Thank you, but
我已经搬了一篮子衣服到楼下了
I already have a load in downstairs,
而且你不会希望我用你的洗衣机洗工作服的
and you really don't want my scrubs in your machine.
我刚在传染病科室上完一轮班 所以
I just finished a rotation in the infectious disease ward, so...
哇哦 我会保持距离
Well, I'll keep my distance.
希望别太远
Hopefully, not too far.
对了 你好像忘记关音响了
Oh, and I think you left your stereo on.
是哦 谢谢
Right. Thank you.
我没给过你钥匙吧
I don't remember giving you a key.
我用得着那玩意儿吗
You really think I'd need one?
我老婆把我赶出来了
My wife kicked me out.
我都不知道你结婚了
I didn't know you were married.
我的事你不知道的多着呢
A lot of things you don't know about me.
对啊 尼克 问题就在这儿
I know, Nick. That's the problem.
有人监听
抱歉 我只能到你这儿来 我实在找不到地方过夜了
I'm sorry to have to do this, but I had no place else to crash.
神盾局有人叛变
还有谁知道你有老婆
Who else knows about your wife?
你和我
只有...
Just...
我的朋友知道
My friends.
我们算朋友
Is that what we are?
那要看你了
That's up to you.
不要相信任何人
Don't trust anyone.
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers?
队长
Captain,
我是神盾局特别行动组13号特工
I'm Agent 13 of S.H.I.E.L.D. Special Service.
凯特
Kate?
我受命保护你
I'm assigned to protect you.
受谁的命令
On whose order?
他的
His.
F受了重伤 已经失去意识了
Foxtrot is down, he's unresponsive.
需要急救人员
I need EMTs.
看到射手了吗
<i>Do we have a 20 on the shooter?</i>
告诉他们我去追了
Tell him I'm in pursuit.
他能挺过来吗
Is he gonna make it?
不知道
I don't know.
跟我说说那个射手
Tell me about the shooter.
他速度很快 很强壮
He's fast. Strong.
有一只金属手臂
Had a metal arm.
能追踪弹道吗
Ballistics?
三发子弹 没有弹道 完全追踪不到
Three slugs, no rifling. Completely untraceable.
苏联制造
Soviet-made.
对
Yeah.
他快不行了 室性心动过速
He's in V-tach.
急救车推进来
Crash cart coming in.
护士 帮我拿一下纱布
Nurse, help me with the drape.
- 血压在下降   - 电除颤
- BP's dropping.   - Defibrillator!
用100焦的单相波
I want you to charge him at 100.
千万不能死 尼克
Don't do this to me, Nick.
大家都后退
Stand back.
三 二
Three, two,
一 离手
one. Clear.
- 脉搏？   - 没有脉搏
- Pulse?   - No pulse.
好 用200焦的单相波
Okay, 200, please.
退后
Stand back!
三 二 一
Three, two, one. Clear!
快给我肾上腺素
Get me epinephrine!
脉搏呢
Pulse?
没有
Negative.
千万别死 尼克 千万别死
Don't do this to me, Nick. Don't do this to me.
现在几点
What's the time?
凌晨一点零三分 医生
1:03, Doctor.
死亡时间 凌晨一点零三分
Time of death, 1:03 a.m.
我得把他带走了
I need to take him.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
Natasha!
弗瑞为什么会去你的公寓
Why was Fury in your apartment?
我也不知道
I don't know.
队长 他们叫你回局里
Cap, they want you back at S.H.I.E.L.D.
好 等一下
Yeah, give me a second.
他们要你现在就回去
They want you now.
知道了
Okay.
你连撒谎都不会
You're a terrible liar.
特战队 护送罗杰斯队长回神盾局
<i>S.T.R.I.K.E. team, escort Captain Rogers</i>
特战队 立刻护送罗杰斯队长回神盾局接受质询
<i>back to S.H.I.E.L.D. immediately for questioning.</i>
我告诉过他
I told him.
- 我们走   - 好
- Let's go.   - Yeah.
特战队 出发
S.T.R.I.K.E., move it out.
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers.
邻居
Neighbour.
队长
Oh. Captain.
我是亚历山大·皮尔斯
I'm Alexander Pierce.
长官 这是我的荣幸
Sir, it's an Honour.
感到荣幸的是我才对 队长
The honour's mine, Captain.
我父亲曾在101空降师服役 进来吧
My father served in the 101st. Come on in.
那张照片是我和弗瑞认识了五年以后才拍的
That photo was taken five years after Nick and I met,
那个时候我在国务院工作 在波哥大
when I was at State Department in Bogota.
当时叛军占领了大使馆
E.L.N. rebels took the embassy,
警卫把我救出来了 但是叛军抓了些人质
and security got me out, but the rebels took hostages.
尼克是当地神盾局的副局长
Nick was Deputy Chief of the S.H.I.E.L.D. station there,
他告诉了我他的计划
and he comes to me with a plan.
他想从下水道突袭大楼
He wants to storm the building through the sewers.
我说 不行 我们得和他们谈判
I said, "No, we'll negotiate."
结果叛军不肯接受谈判 所以双方只好用暴力解决问题了
Turned out, the E.L.N. didn't negotiate, so they put out a kill order.
我们突袭了地下室
They stormed the basement, and what do they find?
结果发现里面是空的
They find it empty.
原来尼克无视了我的命令
Nick had ignored my direct order,
在外国领土实施了一次未经授权的军事行动
and carried out an unauthorised military operation on foreign soil,
他拯救了十几个公务员
and saved the lives of a dozen political officers,
其中包括我女儿
including my daughter.
所以你给他升职了
So you gave him a promotion.
我从没后悔过
I've never had any cause to regret it.
队长 昨晚尼克为什么会在你的公寓里
Captain, why was Nick in your apartment last night?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道你那儿被监听吗
Did you know it was bugged?
我知道 尼克告诉我了
I did, because Nick told me.
他告诉你就是他在监听吗
Did he tell you he was the one who bugged it?
我想给你看点东西
I want you to see something.
巴托克 谁派你来的
<i>Who hired you, Batroc?</i>
那是实时视频吗
Is that live?
对 他们昨晚抓到他的 在阿尔及尔的一个安全屋
Yeah, they picked him up last night in a not-so-safe house in Algiers.
你是说他是嫌疑犯
Are you saying he's a suspect?
刺杀可不是他的强项
Assassination isn't Batroc's line.
不 比这要复杂多了
No, no. It's more complicated than that.
巴图克被匿名雇佣去袭击利莫里亚之星
Batroc was hired anonymously to attack the <i>Lemurian Star.</i>
他们通过电子邮件联系 通过电子转账得到报酬
And he was contacted by email and paid by wire transfer,
然后这些钱转入转出17个虚假账户
and then the money was run through 17 fictitious accounts.
最后到一家控股公司的账上
The last one going to a holding company
公司的注册人是雅各布·韦奇
that was registered to a Jacob Veech.
你觉得我认识他
Am I supposed to know who that is?
不太可能 他六年前就死了
Not likely. Veech died six years ago.
他最后的住址是埃尔姆赫特大道1435号
His last address was 1435 Elmhurst Drive.
我刚认识尼克的时候 他的母亲住在1437号
When I first met Nick, his mother lived at 1437.
你是说尼克雇了那些强盗 为什么
Are you saying Fury hired the pirates? Why?
最合理的解释是
The prevailing theory
这次劫持是为了掩盖他们获取
was that the hijacking was a cover for the acquisition
和出售机密情报的事情
and sale of classified intelligence.
交易谈崩 导致了尼克的死
The sale went sour and that led to Nick's death.
如果你了解尼克·弗瑞的话 就知道这不可能
If you really knew Nick Fury, you'd know that's not true.
那我干嘛找你谈
Why do you think we're talking?
我在理事会占了一席 并不是因为我想
See, I took a seat on the Council not because I wanted to,
只是因为尼克拜托我 因为我们都是现实主义者
but because Nick asked me to, because we were both realists.
我们知道除了外交 高层合作 还有豪言壮语
We knew that, despite all the diplomacy and the handshaking and the rhetoric,
要想打造一个更好的世界
to build a really better world
有时候意味着要把旧的世界推翻
sometimes means having to tear the old one down.
这样就会树敌
And that makes enemies.
那些人说你肮脏不堪 只是因为你有胆量
Those people that call you dirty because you got the guts
把手伸进泥里 试着去创造一些更好的东西
to stick your hands in the mud and try to build something better.
每次想到那些人现在正春风得意
And the idea that those people could be happy today
就让我非常 非常愤怒
makes me really, really angry.
队长 你是尼克生前见到的最后一个人
Captain, you were the last one to see Nick alive.
这不会是巧合
I don't think that's an accident.
我觉得你也这么想
And I don't think you do, either.
所以我再问一次
So, I'm gonna ask again.
他干嘛去你那儿
Why was he there?
他告诉我不要相信任何人
He told me not to trust anyone.
其中也包括他自己吗
I wonder if that included him.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这是他最后一句话
Those were his last words.
失陪
Excuse me.
队长
Captain,
有人谋杀了我的朋友 我一定会查出真相
somebody murdered my friend and I'm gonna find out why.
如果有人敢阻拦我 我会让他后悔的
Anyone gets in my way, they're gonna regret it.
不管是谁
Anyone.
明白了
Understood.
调度控制中心
Operations Control.
确认
<i>Confirmed.</i>
叫全体特战队员就位
Keep all S.T.R.I.K.E. personnel on site.
- 明白   - 是 长官
- Understood.   - Yes, sir.
- 鉴证科   - 确认
- Forensics.   - <i>Confirmed.</i>
队长
Cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
取证组在屋顶找到了些纤维 叫我们去看看
Evidence Response found some fibres on the roof they want us to see.
需要我通知应对小组做好准备吗
You want me to get the Tac team ready?
不用 先去看看是什么再说
No, let's wait and see what it is first.
好的
Right.
现在是什么情况
What's the status so far?
- 行政层   - 确认
- Administrations level.   - <i>Confirmed.</i>
请让一下
Excuse me.
弗瑞的事儿我很遗憾
I'm sorry about what happened with Fury.
他真不走运
It's messed up, what happened to him.
谢谢
Thank you.
档案室
Records.
确认
Confirmed.
我们动手之前
Before we get started,
有人想出去吗
does anyone want to get out?
调动特战队去25楼
Mobilise S.T.R.I.K.E. units, 25th floor.
哇哦 肌肉男
Whoa, big guy.
我只想告诉你 队长 这不是私人恩怨
I just want you to know, Cap, this isn't personal!
感觉就是私人恩怨
It kind of feels personal.
放下盾牌 举起双手
Drop the shield and put your hands in the air!
投降吧 罗杰斯 把门打开
Give it up, Rogers! Get that door open!
你无路可逃
You have nowhere to go!
这怎么可能
Are you kidding me?
他朝车库去了 立刻封锁大桥
He's headed for the garage. Lock down the bridge.
解除战备 罗杰斯队长 解除战备
<i>Stand down, Captain Rogers. Stand down.</i>
重复 解除战备
<i>Repeat, stand down.</i>
所有人请注意
Eyes here.
无论你手头正在做什么 先放下
Whatever your Op is, bury it.
这是一级战备
This is Level One.
联系交通部
Contact DOT.
把这一区所有交通灯调为红灯
All traffic lights in the district go red.
关闭华盛顿机场 杜勒斯机场
Shut all runways at BWI,
里根国际机场的所有跑道
IAD and Reagan.
把所有的监控镜头转接到这个屏幕上来
All security cameras in the city go through this monitor right here.
审查所有通讯设备
Scan all open sources,
手机 计算机
phones, computers,
掌上电脑 所有设备
PDAs. Whatever.
如果有人发关于这人的任何消息
If someone tweets about this guy,
我要立刻知道
I want to know about it.
恕我直言 如果神盾局决定搜捕美国队长
With all due respect, if S.H.I.E.L.D. is conducting
我们有权知道原因
a manhunt for Captain America we deserve to know why.
因为他撒谎了
Because he lied to us.
罗杰斯掌握有关弗瑞长官死因的信息
Captain Rogers has information regarding the death of Director Fury.
却拒绝对我们报告
He refused to share it.
我知道这一点你们很难接受
As difficult as this is to accept,
但美国队长现在确实是神盾局的逃犯了
Captain America is a fugitive from S.H.I.E.L.D.
- 它在哪儿   - 很安全
- Where is it?   - Safe.
- 说详细点儿   - 你从哪儿弄来的
- Do better.   - Where did you get it?
我为什么要告诉你
Why would I tell you?
弗瑞给你的吧 为什么
Fury gave it to you. Why?
- 里面是什么   - 不知道
- What's on it?   - I don't know.
别再撒谎了
Stop lying.
罗杰斯 我只是装作什么都知道而已
I only act like I know everything, Rogers.
你知道海盗是弗瑞雇的 对吧
I bet you knew Fury hired the pirates, didn't you?
有道理 那船有问题 弗瑞想上去 你也是吧
Well, it makes sense. The ship was dirty, Fury needed a way in, so do you.
我可不想再问你一遍
I'm not gonna ask you again.
我知道谁杀了弗瑞
I know who killed Fury.
多数情报机构不相信他的存在
Most of the intelligence community doesn't believe he exists.
相信其存在的人把他叫做冬日战士
The ones that do call him the Winter Soldier.
过去50多年里
He's credited with over two dozen assassinations
他被认为是20多起刺杀案的凶手
in the last 50 years.
你想说这是个鬼故事么
So he's a ghost story.
五年前我护送一个核物理工程师离开伊朗
Five years ago, I was escorting a nuclear engineer out of Iran.
有人在奥德萨附近打爆了我的车胎
Somebody shot out my tyres near Odessa.
车失控后直冲悬崖
We lost control, went straight over a cliff.
我们逃了出来
I pulled us out.
当时冬日战士在那
But the Winter Soldier was there.
我护在工程师前面 他的子弹穿过了我
I was covering my engineer so he shot him
击中工程师
straight through me.
苏联子弹
Soviet slug.
没有弹道 再见了 比基尼
No rifling. Bye-bye, bikinis.
你穿那个一定很难看
Yeah, I bet you look terrible in them now.
追踪他根本不可能 我试过了
Going after him is a dead end. I know, I've tried.
像你说的 他就是个幽灵
Like you said, he's a ghost story.
那么就让我看看这个幽灵要做什么
Well, let's find out what the ghost wants.
尼克弗瑞被残忍至此地杀害
<i>Nick Fury was murdered in cold blood.</i>
任何通情理的人
To any reasonable person,
都会认为他是个烈士而非叛徒
that would make him a martyr, not a traitor.
知道为什么他是个叛徒么
You know what makes him a traitor?
他雇了佣兵去劫持自己的船
Hiring a mercenary to hijack his own ship.
尼克弗瑞利用你们的友谊
Nick Fury used your friendship
迫使理事会推迟洞察计划
to coerce this Council into delaying Project Insight.
正因他知道这个计划会暴露他的不法勾当
A project he knew would expose his own illegal operations.
往轻了说 就是他欺骗了你 往重了说
At best, he lied to you. At worst...
你是叫我引咎辞职吗
Are you calling for my resignation?
我手头上就有纸笔
I've got a pen and paper right here.
这件事我们稍后会讨论的
That discussion can be tabled for a later time.
也就是说你们真的打算讨论
But you do want to have a discussion?
我们已经讨论过了 部长阁下
We've already had it, Mr Secretary.
理事会决议立即重启洞察计划
This Council moves to immediately reactivate Project Insight.
如果你想发火 就趁现在吧
If you want to say something snappy, now would be a good time.
逃跑的首要法则就是不要跑 用走的
First rule of going on the run is don't run, walk.
如果我穿着这鞋子跑 鞋会跑掉的
If I run in these shoes, they're gonna fall off.
这个驱动里带有6级追踪定位程序
The drive has a Level Six homing program, so as soon as we boot up
我们一旦启用 神盾局就会知道我们的位置
S.H.I.E.L.D. will know exactly where we are.
我们有多少时间
How much time will we have?
大约9分钟
About nine minutes from
从现在开始
now.
弗瑞对那艘船的判断是对的
Fury was right about that ship.
有人想要隐藏什么
Somebody's trying to hide something.
这U盘受人工智能保护
This drive is protected by some sort of AI.
它不断地自我重写来撤消我的命令
It keeps rewriting itself to counter my commands.
你能搞定它吗
Can you override it?
开发这玩意的人比我聪明那么一点儿
The person who developed this is slightly smarter than me.
就一点儿
Slightly.
我要试试运行一个追踪程序
I'm gonna try running a tracer.
神盾局开发这个程序
This is a program that S.H.I.E.L.D. developed
是为了追踪敌对恶意软件
to track hostile malware,
所以即使我们不能读取文件
so if we can't read the file,
我们或许能找出它的来源
maybe we can find out where it came from.
嘿 你们需要什么帮助吗
Can I help you guys with anything?
噢 不必了 我和我的未婚夫正在挑蜜月旅行地
Oh, no. My fiancé was just helping me with some honeymoon destinations.
没错 我们快结婚了
Right. We're getting married.
恭喜 你们想好了去哪儿吗
Congratulations. Where are you guys thinking about going?
新泽西州
New Jersey.
我有副一模一样的眼镜
I have the exact same glasses.
你们俩简直就是双胞胎
Wow, you two are practically twins.
是啊 我也想啊
Yeah, I wish.
型男
Specimen.
那么有什么需要的话就找我吧 我叫艾伦
If you guys need anything, I've been Aaron.
谢了
Thank you.
- 你说的9分钟 快点儿吧   - 别紧张
- You said nine minutes. Come on.   - Relax.
搞定
Got it.
新泽西州 维顿
你知道这地方？
You know it?
以前知道  行动
I used to. Let's go.
标准应对组
Standard Tac team.
后面两个 侧方两个
Two behind, two across,
迎面两个
and two coming straight at us.
如果被缠住了 我们从南面扶梯前往地铁站
If they make us, I'll engage, you hit the south escalator to the metro.
闭嘴 搂住我 随便笑两声
Shut up and put your arm around me. Laugh at something I said.
- 什么   - 快笑
- What?   - Do it.
这里不是信号源
Negative at the source.
一层一层楼地搜
Give me a floor rundown.
三楼没有
<i>Negative on three.</i>
二楼没有
<i>Negative on two.</i>
彻底搜查上层 从上往下搜
Snake the upper levels. Work down to me.
- 吻我   - 什么
- Kiss me.   - What?
公众场合亲密举动总会令人不自在
Public displays of affection make people very uncomfortable.
没错 是这样
Yes, they do.
现在还不自在
You still uncomfortable?
我会换个词形容
It's not exactly the word I would use.
欢迎来到新泽西州 花园洲
队长大人是从哪儿学的偷车啊
Where did Captain America learn how to steal a car?
纳粹德国
Nazi Germany.
而且我们是借 别把脚放上面
And we're borrowing. Take your feet off the dash.
好吧 我有个问题问你 你可以不回答
All right, I have a question for you, which you do not have to answer.
其实我觉得不回答
I feel like, if you don't answer it though,
- 也是一种回答 你懂吧   - 什么
- you're kind of answering it, you know.   - What?
这是你1945年来第一次接吻吗
Was that your first kiss since 1945?
- 有那么差劲吗   - 我可没这么说
- That bad, huh?   - I didn't say that.
听上去就是这个意思
Well, it kind of sounds like that's what you're saying.
不不
No, I didn't.
我就是好奇你练过接吻没有
I just wondered how much practice you've had.
- 我不需要练习   - 任何人都需要
- You don't need practice.   - Everybody needs practice.
这不是我1945年来第一次接吻
It was not my first kiss since 1945.
我95岁 但不代表我是个死人
I'm 95, I'm not dead.
也没有特定的心上人吧
Nobody special, though?
随你信不信吧
Believe it or not, it's kind of hard
找个能和我有类似人生经历的人很难
to find someone with shared life experience.
这有什么啊 编个故事不就完了
Well, that's all right. You just make something up.
- 就像你？   - 我不知道
- What, like you?   - I don't know.
视情况而定吧
The truth is a matter of circumstance.
你不可能以同一面孔去应对所有事 所有人 所有情景
It's not all things to all people, all the time.
我也一样
Neither am I.
这样活着很累
That's a tough way to live.
能活着就挺好了
It's a good way not to die, though.
当你不清楚一个人的真实样子
You know, it's kind of hard to trust someone,
你很难去相信他
when you don't know who that someone really is.
是啊
Yeah.
你希望我是谁
Who do you want me to be?
朋友怎么样
How about a friend?
你这种人或许不太适合干这行 罗杰斯
Well, there's a chance you might be in the wrong business, Rogers.
就是这里
This is it.
文件就是从这儿来的
The file came from these coordinates.
我也是
So did I.
我以前在这个营地训练
This camp is where I was trained.
变化大吗
Change much?
还好
A little.
跟上啊 姑娘们
Pick up the pace, ladies!
跟上 跟上
Let's go! Let's go!
步子加快
Double time!
快点儿 罗杰斯 快点儿
Come on, Rogers, move it!
跟上 归队
Come on, fall in!
罗杰斯
Rogers!
我说归队
I said fall in!
这里没戏
This is a dead end.
没有生命迹象 没有信号波段 无线电波都没有
Zero heat signatures, zero waves, not even radio.
写程序的人准是用了路由器耍人玩儿
Whoever wrote the file must have used a router to throw people off.
怎么了
What is it?
军规有定 营房500码之内
Army regulations forbid storing munitions
禁止存放军需物品
within 500 yards of the barracks.
这栋建筑盖错地方了
This building is in the wrong place.
这是神盾局
This is S.H.I.E.L.D.
可能是它成立的地方
Maybe where it started.
这是斯塔克的父亲
And there's Stark's father.
霍华德
Howard.
这姑娘是谁
Who's the girl?
这已经是秘密办公室了
If you're already working in a secret office,
为什么还要把电梯藏起来
why do you need to hide the elevator?
这不可能是数据源 设备太落后了
This can't be the data point. This technology is ancient.
是否启动系统
Y-E-S 是
Y-E-S spells yes.
要玩个游戏吗
Shall we play a game?
- 这是一部经典电影里的台词   - 我知道 我看过
- It's from a movie that was really...   - I know, I saw it.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯
<i>Rogers, Steven,</i>
1918年出生
<i>born 1918.</i>
娜塔莎·诺曼诺夫
<i>Romanoff, Natalia Alianovna,</i>
1984年出生
<i>born 1984.</i>
这是什么录像吧
It's some kind of recording.
我可不是什么录像 小姐
<i>I am not a recording, Fr?ulein.</i>
我也许不再是
<i>I may not be the man I was</i>
1945年被队长抓进监狱的那个人了
<i>when the Captain took me prisoner in 1945.</i>
但我还是我
<i>But I am.</i>
你认识这什么东西
You know this thing?
阿尔尼姆·佐拉是为红骷髅卖命的德国科学家
Arnim Zola was a German scientist who worked for the Red Skull.
他已经死了很多年了
He's been dead for years.
首先纠正一下 我是瑞士人
<i>First correction, I am Swiss.</i>
其次 看看你周围吧
<i>Second, look around you.</i>
我可比以往任何时候都要精神
<i>I have never been more alive.</i>
1972年 我被判癌症晚期
<i>In 1972, I received a terminal diagnosis.</i>
科学已经无法拯救我的身体
<i>Science could not save my body.</i>
但我的大脑值得挽救和保存
<i>My mind, however, that was worth saving,</i>
它就根植在这20万英尺的数据线中
<i>on 200,000 feet of databanks.</i>
你们此刻就站在我的大脑内部
<i>You are standing in my brain.</i>
- 你怎么到这里来的   - 被请来的
- How did you get here?   <i>- Invited.</i>
二战后的回形针行动
It was Operation Paperclip after World War II.
神盾局纳入了不少具有战略价值的德国科学家
S.H.I.E.L.D. recruited German scientists with strategic value.
他们认为我能为他们事业提供助力
<i>They thought I could help their cause.</i>
其实这也正好帮到了我自己
<i>I also helped my own.</i>
九头蛇和红骷髅一起死了
HYDRA died with the Red Skull.
砍掉一个蛇头 会长出两个新的来
<i>Cut off one head, two more shall take its place.</i>
证明给我看
Prove it.
正在读取存档
<i>Accessing archive.</i>
九头蛇的成立 基于这样的理念
<i>HYDRA was founded on the belief that humanity</i>
就是人类不可被放任地赋予自由
<i>could not be trusted with its own freedom.</i>
我们没有意识到的是
<i>What we did not realise was that if you try</i>
如果你试图夺走自由 他们就会反抗
<i>to take that freedom, they resist.</i>
战争给我们很多教训
<i>The war taught us much.</i>
人类需要放弃自由 自愿放弃
<i>Humanity needed to surrender its freedom willingly.</i>
战争结束后 神盾局成立
<i>After the war, S.H.I.E.L.D. was founded,</i>
我也被招募进来
<i>and I was recruited.</i>
于是新的九头蛇重生了
<i>The new HYDRA grew.</i>
成为神盾局体内一个美丽的寄生虫
<i>A beautiful parasite inside S.H.I.E.L.D.</i>
在过去70年里
<i>For 70 years,</i>
九头蛇一直在秘密的助长各种危机 从战争中获益
<i>HYDRA has been secretly feeding crisis, reaping war,</i>
当历史不肯配合的时候
<i>and when history did not cooperate,</i>
它就改变历史
<i>history was changed.</i>
不可能 神盾局一定会阻止你的
That's impossible. S.H.I.E.L.D. would have stopped you.
意外总会发生
<i>Accidents will happen.</i>
九头蛇创造了一个极其混乱的世界
<i>HYDRA created a world so chaotic</i>
人类到最后终于准备好 牺牲他们的自由
<i>that humanity is finally ready to sacrifice its freedom</i>
来换取安全
<i>to gain its security.</i>
一旦进化程序全部完成
<i>Once a purification process is complete,</i>
九头蛇将建立起统治世界的新秩序
<i>HYDRA'S new world order will arise.</i>
是我们赢了 队长
<i>We won, Captain.</i>
你的生存和死亡 价值是一样的
<i>Your death amounts to the same as your life.</i>
都等于零
<i>A zero sum.</i>
我说过了…
<i>As I was saying...</i>
U盘里是什么
What's on this drive?
洞察计划当然需要洞察力
<i>Project Insight requires insight.</i>
我写了一套算法
<i>So, I wrote an algorithm.</i>
什么算法 有什么用
What kind of algorithm? What does it do?
这个问题的答案很迷人
<i>The answer to your question is fascinating.</i>
只可惜 我没办法把答案告诉两个死人
<i>Unfortunately, you shall be too dead to hear it.</i>
史蒂夫 有个飞行物
Steve, we got a bogey.
短程弹道导弹
Short range ballistic.
- 最多还有30秒   - 谁发射的
- 30 seconds tops.   - Who fired it?
神盾局
S.H.I.E.L.D.
真是不好意思 我一直在拖延时间 队长
<i>I am afraid I have been stalling, Captain.</i>
认命吧
<i>Admit it.</i>
这样其实更好
<i>It's better this way.</i>
我们都一样
<i>We are, both of us,</i>
时间不多了
<i>out of time.</i>
去叫他过来
Call in the asset.
我得走了 皮尔斯先生
I'm going to go, Mr Pierce.
在我走之前您还需要什么吗
You need anything before I leave?
不 没事儿了 蕾娜塔 你可以回家了
No... Uh, it's fine, Renata, you can go home.
好的 晚安
Okay. Night-night.
晚安
Good night.
喝牛奶么
Want some milk?
时间表提前了
The timetable has moved.
我们的时间很有限
Our window is limited.
两个6级威胁的目标
Two targets, Level Six.
他们害我损失了佐拉
They already cost me Zola.
10小时之内 我要确认他们死亡
I want confirmed death in 10 hours.
抱歉 皮尔斯先生 我…
Sorry, Mr Pierce, I...
我忘了拿
I forgot my
手机
phone.
哦 蕾娜塔 你真应该先敲门的
Oh, Renata, I wish you would have knocked.
嘿 哥们儿
Hey, man.
抱歉突然过来 我们得找个地方躲一下
I'm sorry about this. We need a place to lay low.
我们认识的人都想杀了我们
Everyone we know is trying to kill us.
不是每个人
Not everyone.
- 你还好吧   - 还好
- You okay?   - Yeah.
你怎么了
What's going on?
当初加入神盾局时 我以为这是条正途
When I first joined S.H.I.E.L.D. I thought I was going straight.
现在想来我不过是出了克格勃又为九头蛇卖命
But I guess I just traded in the KGB for HYDRA.
现俄罗斯联邦安全局
我以为我知道自己在为谁说谎
I thought I knew whose lies I was telling,
但是现在我已经分不清了
but I guess I can't tell the difference any more.
你这种人可能不太适合干这行
There's a chance you might be in the wrong business.
我欠你条命
I owe you.
这没什么
It's okay.
如果当时情况反过来
If it was the other way around,
如果需要我来救你
and it was down to me to save your life,
实话告诉我
now you be honest with me,
你相信我会救你吗
would you trust me to do it?
现在我会
I would now.
而且我一向都说实话
And I'm always honest.
你刚发现自己当初白白牺牲了
Well, you seem pretty chipper
可你好像还挺高兴
for someone who just found out they died for nothing.
这个嘛 好歹知道对手是谁了
Well, guess I just like to know who I'm fighting.
我做了早餐
I made breakfast.
如果你们要吃的话
If you guys eat that sort of thing.
现在的问题是
So, the question is,
神盾局里谁有权发动国内导弹袭击
who at S.H.I.E.L.D. could launch a domestic missile strike?
皮尔斯
Pierce.
他碰巧是世界上最安全大楼的头儿
Who happens to be sitting on top of the most secure building in the world.
不止他一个人
But he's not working alone.
佐拉的算法在利莫里亚星之星上
Zola's algorithm was on the <i>Lemurian Star.</i>
那就是加斯帕·希特维尔了
So it was Jasper Sitwell.
所以真正的问题是 两个身处华府的头号通缉犯
So, the real question is, how do the two most wanted people
要怎么在光天化日之下 绑架神盾局官员呢？
in Washington kidnap a S.H.I.E.L.D. officer in broad daylight?
答案是 用不着
The answer is, you don't.
- 这是什么   - 就当是我的简历吧
- What's this?   - Call it a résumé.
这是巴卡马拉
Is this Bakhmala?
哈利的哈迪奥任务是你干的
The Khalid Khandil mission, that was you?
你没说过他是个空降救援兵
You didn't say he was a Pararescue.
- 这是莱利   - 是的
- Is this Riley?   - Yeah.
我听说他们不能派直升机 因为有火箭弹
I heard they couldn't bring in the choppers because of the RPGs.
你用的什么 隐形降落伞
What did you use? A stealth chute?
不
No.
用这个
These.
我以为你是个飞行员
I thought you said you were a pilot.
我可没这么说过
I never said pilot.
我不能要求你这么做 山姆
I can't ask you to do this, Sam.
你有充足的理由退役
You got out for a good reason.
伙计 美国队长需要我的帮助
Dude, Captain America needs my help.
没有比这更好的理由让我重出江湖了
There's no better reason to get back in.
我们在哪儿能搞到这东西
Where can we get our hands on one of these things?
最后一批在米德堡基地
The last one is at Fort Meade.
在三道严防驻守的大门和12英尺厚的钢铁墙后面
Behind three guarded gates and a 12-inch steel wall.
应该不是问题
Shouldn't be a problem.
EXO-7
猎鹰计划
机密
听着 我今晚得飞回去
Listen, I got to fly home tonight
因为选民方面有点问题
because I got some constituency problem
我得去做做姿态
and I got to press the flesh.
有什么特别的选民吗 参议员先生
Any constituent in particular, Mr Senator?
呃 没有 没什么
Oh, no, not really.
23岁 挺火辣的
Twenty-three, kind of hot.
很性感
Real hot, you know?
大概想当个记者吧 我也不知道
Wants to be a reporter, I think. I don't know.
那时候谁会留心听这些
Who listens at that point?
听上去不是什么麻烦
Doesn't sound like much of a problem to me.
是吗 她可把我背都给挠疼了
Really? Because she's killing my back.
这儿不是谈论这个的地方
But this isn't the place to talk about it.
胸针不错
This is a nice pin.
- 谢谢   - 过来
- Thank you.   - Come here.
九头蛇万岁
Hail HYDRA.
- 看见了吧   - 对 我看见了
- See, it's right there...   - Yeah, I just saw that.
- 我该去做个检查吗   - 最好去看一下
- Should I get it checked?   - I think you should.
亚历山大·皮尔斯来电
让我单独呆会儿
I need a minute.
去把车开过来
Bring the car around.
喂 长官
Yes, sir?
希特韦尔特工 午餐怎么样
<i>Agent Sitwell, how was lunch?</i>
我听说这儿的蟹肉饼味道还不错
<i>I hear the crab cakes here are delicious.</i>
你是谁
Who is this?
你十点钟方向那个带墨镜的帅哥
<i>The good-looking guy in the sunglasses, your 10 o'clock.</i>
另一边
<i>Your other 10 o'clock.</i>
这下对了
<i>There you go.</i>
你想干什么
What do you want?
我要你走到你右边那个拐角
<i>You're gonna go around the corner to your right.</i>
第二个停车格有辆灰色的车
There's a grey car two spaces down.
咱俩去兜个风
You and I are gonna take a ride.
我为什么要听你的
And why would I do that?
因为那条领带看起来很贵
Because that tie looks really expensive,
我真不忍心给弄坏了
<i>and I'd hate to mess it up.</i>
告诉我佐拉算法是怎么回事
Tell me about Zola's algorithm.
从来没听说过
Never heard of it.
你在利莫里亚星号上干嘛
What were you doing on the <i>Lemurian Star?</i>
我在吐 我晕船
I was throwing up. I get seasick.
难道你会因为这点小事儿就把我从这儿扔出去
Is this little display meant to insinuate that you're gonna throw me off the roof?
这不是你的风格 罗杰斯
Because it's really not your style, Rogers.
你说得对
You're right.
不是我的风格
It's not.
是她的
It's hers.
噢 等等 那我说财务部那女孩怎么样 劳拉什么的…
Oh, wait. What about that girl from Accounting, Laura...
有唇环的那个对吧
Lillian. Lip piercing, right?
对 那妹子挺可爱
Yeah, she's cute.
是啊 但口味太重了
Yeah. I'm not ready for that.
佐拉算法是套程序
Zola's algorithm is a program
用来挑选
for choosing
- 洞察计划的目标   - 什么目标
- insight's targets.   - What targets?
你
You!
开罗的电视主持 国防部的副局长
A TV anchor in Cairo, the Under Secretary of Defence,
爱荷华州高中毕业生代表
a high school Valedictorian in Iowa City,
布鲁斯·班纳 史蒂芬·斯特雷齐
Bruce Banner, Stephen Strange, anyone who's a threat
指绿巨人和奇异博士
任何威胁到九头蛇的人
to HYDRA.
现在的和未来的
Now, or in the future.
未来的？ 它怎么能知道
In the future? How could it know?
它怎么能不知道
How could it not?
21世纪就是本电子书
The 21st century is a digital book.
佐拉教会九头蛇怎样阅读它
Zola taught HYDRA how to read it.
你的银行记录
Your bank records,
医疗病史 投票模式
medical histories, voting patterns,
电子邮件 电话记录 还有该死的大学考试成绩
emails, phone calls, your damn SAT scores!
佐拉算法会通过评估人们的过去
Zola's algorithm evaluates people's past
来预测他们的未来
to predict their future.
然后呢
And what then?
老天爷 皮尔斯知道了一定会杀了我的
Oh, my God. Pierce is gonna kill me.
然后呢
What then?
然后洞察天空母舰会把名单上的人除掉
Then the Insight helicarriers scratch people off the list.
一次性几百万个
A few million at a time.
九头蛇讨厌泄密
HYDRA doesn't like leaks.
那你的嘴怎么这么松
Then why don't you try sticking a cork in it?
洞察计划将在16小时后启动
Insight's launching in 16 hours.
我们时间有点紧
We're cutting it a little bit close here.
我知道 我们利用他通过DNA扫描
I know. We'll use him to bypass the DNA scans
直接进入天空母舰
and access the helicarriers directly.
你说啥 你疯了吗
What? Are you crazy?
这主意简直糟透了
That is a terrible, terrible idea.
我靠
Shit!
抓紧了
Hang on!
我搞定那女的 你们去找另外一个
I have her. Find him.
快走 这儿有我
Go! I got this!
高速公路一带发生枪战
<i>Taking fire above and below expressway.</i>
市民受到威胁 重复 市民受到威胁
<i>Civilians threatened. Repeat, civilians threatened.</i>
弗吉尼亚大道2300街区有一个着陆点
<i>I make an LZ, 2300 block of Virginia Avenue.</i>
两分钟后碰头
<i>Rendezvous, two minutes.</i>
快躲开
Get out of the way!
Stay out of the way!
巴基
Bucky?
谁特么是巴基
Who the hell is Bucky?
放下盾牌 队长 跪在地上
Drop the shield, Cap! Get on your knees!
跪下
Get on your knees!
跪下 立刻 跪在地上
Get down, get down! Get on your knees!
跪下
Down!
别动
Don't move.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
这儿不行 这儿不行
Not here. Not here!
是他
<i>It was him.</i>
他就这么看着我 就像根本不认得我
He looked right at me like he didn't even know me.
这怎么可能 都过去70年了
How is that even possible? It was, like, 70 years ago.
是佐拉
Zola.
巴基以前的部队在1943年被俘虏了
Bucky's whole unit was captured in '43.
佐拉在他身上做实验
Zola experimented on him.
不管他做了什么 那个实验让巴基在坠崖后活了下来
Whatever he did helped Bucky survive the fall.
他们肯定找到了他
They must have found him and...
但那不是你的错 史蒂夫
None of that's your fault, Steve.
在我一无所有的时候 我还有巴基
Even when I had nothing, I had Bucky.
你们得找个医生来
We need to get a doctor here.
不压住伤口的话
If we don't put pressure on that wound,
她在车上就会失血而亡的
she's gonna bleed out here in the truck.
这玩意儿挤得我脑袋疼死了
Ah. That thing was squeezing my brain.
这谁
Who is this guy?
三个坑 开始挖
Three holes. Start digging.
有人中枪 至少失了一品脱量的血
GSW. She's lost at least a pint.
可能是两品脱
Maybe two.
- 交给我吧   - 先带她去见个人
- Let me take her.   - She'll want to see him first.
你们可来了
About damn time.
脊柱撕伤
Lacerated spinal column,
胸骨断裂
cracked sternum,
锁骨粉碎
shattered collarbone,
肝脏穿孔
perforated liver,
头还疼的要命
and one hell of a headache.
别忘了 还有肺部破裂
Don't forget your collapsed lung.
这个可不能忘
Let's not forget that.
除了这些都挺好
Otherwise, I'm good.
他们给你开膛 你的心脏都停跳了
They cut you open. Your heart stopped.
河豚毒素B
Tetrodotoxin B.
能把心跳减至每分钟一下
Slows the pulse to one beat a minute.
班纳为了控制情绪紧张发明的
Banner developed it for stress.
对他不太管用 但在我这儿挺好使
Didn't work so great for him, but we found a use for it.
为什么全部都要保密 为什么不告诉我们
Why all the secrecy? Why not just tell us?
为了能确保计划成功实施
Any attempt on the Director's life had to look successful.
你已经死了 不能再被杀死一次
Can't kill you if you're already dead.
再说了
Besides,
我也不知道神盾局里还有谁能相信
I wasn't sure who to trust.
巴恩斯中士
Sergeant Barnes.
巴基 不
Bucky, no!
改造程序已经开始了
<i>The procedure has already started.</i>
你将会成为九头蛇的新武器
<i>You are to be the new fist of HYDRA.</i>
把他冷冻起来
<i>Put him on ice.</i>
长官
Sir.
他不稳定
He's unstable.
反复无常
Erratic.
任务汇报
Mission report.
马上做任务汇报
Mission report now.
桥上的那个人
The man on the bridge.
他是谁
Who was he?
这周你执行另一个任务时见过他
You met him earlier this week on another assignment.
我认识他
I knew him.
你做的事是为全人类造福
Your work has been a gift to mankind.
你塑造了这个世界
You shaped the century.
现在我需要你再做一次
And I need you to do it one more time.
人类社会现在处在秩序和混乱的临界点
Society's at a tipping point between order and chaos.
明天早上我们要推它一把
And tomorrow morning, we're gonna give it a push.
不过 你不完成任务 我就没法动手
But, if you don't do your part, I can't do mine.
九头蛇就没法带给世界它应得的自由
And HYDRA can't give the world the freedom it deserves.
可我认识他
But I knew him.
给他准备
Prep him.
他脱离低温冰冻太久了
He's been out of cryo freeze too long.
那就给他洗脑 重新来过
Then wipe him and start over.
这个人拒绝接受诺贝尔和平奖
This man declined the Nobel Peace Prize.
他说 和平不是一项成就
He said peace wasn't an achievement,
而是一种责任
it was a responsibility.
瞧 就是因为这种人害得我不敢相信别人
See, it's stuff like this that gives me trust issues.
我们必须阻止发射
We have to stop the launch.
我觉得理事会不会接我电话的
I don't think the Council's accepting my calls any more.
这是什么
What's that?
当天空母舰飞到三千英尺高
Once the helicarriers reach 3,000 feet,
它们会和洞察卫星组成三角形 然后彻底武器化
they'll triangulate with Insight satellites, becoming fully weaponised.
我们得攻击那些天空航母
We need to breach those carriers
把定位刀锋换成我们自己的
and replace their targeting blades with our own.
只换一两个没用
One or two won't cut it.
我们必须把三架天空母舰都连上
We need to link all three carriers for this to work,
因为即使只剩一架能正常运作
because if even one of those ships remains operational,
还是会有很多人被杀死
a whole lot of people are gonna die.
我们不得不假设那上面都是九头蛇的人
We have to assume everyone aboard those carriers is HYDRA.
我们得闯过他们 把刀锋服务器插进去
We have to get past them, insert these server blades.
也许 只能说也许 我们能抢救
And maybe, just maybe we can salvage what's left...
我们不抢救
We're not salvaging anything.
我们要摧毁天空航母 尼克
We're not just taking down the carriers, Nick.
还有神盾局
We're taking down S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局和这事无关
S.H.I.E.L.D. had nothing to do with this.
你把任务交给我 我就这么干
You gave me this mission. This is how it ends.
神盾局叛变了 这是你自己说的
S.H.I.E.L.D.'s been compromised. You said so yourself.
九头蛇在你眼皮子底下壮大 却没人发现
HYDRA grew right under your nose and nobody noticed.
你觉得我们为什么要在这个山洞里见面 我早就注意到了
Why do you think we're meeting in this cave? I noticed.
在你注意到之前有多少人白白牺牲了
How many paid the price before you did?
我不知道巴恩斯的事儿
Look, I didn't know about Barnes.
就算知道 你会告诉我吗
Even if you had, would you have told me?
你还打算分割管理吗
Or would you have compartmentalised that, too?
神盾局 九头蛇
S.H.I.E.L.D., HYDRA,
一个都不留
it all goes.
他说得对
He's right.
别看我
Don't look at me.
他干嘛我干嘛 就是慢了点儿
I do what he does, just slower.
好吧
Well...
现在我们听你的命令 队长
It looks like you're giving the orders now, Captain.
我们到处在找你
<i>We looked for you, after.</i>
我爸妈想开车送你去墓地
<i>My folks wanted to give you a ride to the cemetery.</i>
我知道 对不起 我只是...想一个人去
I know, I'm sorry. I just kind of wanted to be alone.
葬礼怎么样
How was it?
还行
It was okay.
我妈葬在我爸边上
She's next to Dad.
我想问你...
I was gonna ask...
我知道你想问什么  我只是...
I know what you're gonna say, Buck. I just...
我们像小时候那样
We can put the couch cushions on the floor
把沙发垫铺在地板上
like when we were kids.
会很开心的 你只要帮我擦擦鞋...
It'll be fun. All you got to do is shine my shoes,
或者到个垃圾什么的
maybe take out the trash.
来吧
Come on.
谢谢你 巴基 不过我自己能行
Thank you, Buck, but I can get by on my own.
问题是...你用不着这样
The thing is, you don't have to.
我会一直陪你到最后的 哥们儿
I'm with you to the end of the line, pal.
他一定会在那
He's gonna be there, you know.
我知道
I know.
管他以前什么样 现在的他
Look, whoever he used to be and the guy he is now,
已经不是你的朋友了
I don't think he's the kind you save.
而是你的敌人
He's the kind you stop.
我可能下不了手
I don't know if I can do that.
他可不会让你有的选
Well, he might not give you a choice.
他不记得你
He doesn't know you.
他会的
He will.
到时间了 准备行动
Gear up. It's time.
你穿这个去
You gonna wear that?
不 要去打仗 就得穿军装
No. If you're gonna fight a war, you got to wear a uniform.
哦天哪
Oh, man.
我这饭碗算是砸了
I am so fired.
进入最后发射序列
<i>We are in final launch sequence.</i>
洞察机库处于警戒状态
准备开始制导
We are go on guidance.
所有人员请前往发射台
<i>All personnel to launch stations.</i>
飞行愉快吗
And how was your flight?
很不错
Lovely.
但机场到这儿的路上不怎么样
The ride from the airport, less so.
抱歉 神盾局没法控制一切
Sadly, S.H.I.E.L.D. can't control everything.
包括美国队长
Including Captain America.
这个装置是通过生物识别控制的
This facility is biometrically controlled.
能让你们在这里畅行无阻
And these will give you unrestricted access.
我把车停那儿两个月了
I've been parking there for two months.
- 可这是他的车位   - 他去哪儿了
- But it's his spot.   - So where's he been?
大概去阿富汗了
I think Afghanistan.
不行 DT-6 有飞机要降落
Negative DT Six. The pattern is full.
他应该说点儿什么
Well, he could've said something.
一定是卫星天线
Must be the dish.
我去看一下
I'll check it out.
三曲翼命令 要求清场 准备发射
<i>Triskelion command request we clear the area for launch.</i>
请让一下
Excuse us.
我知道这一路有很多颠簸
<i>I know the road hasn't exactly been smooth,</i>
你们当中有些人还想把我从车里踢出去
and some of you would have gladly kicked me out of the car along the way.
终于我们到了
Finally, we're here.
全世界应该感谢我们
And the world should be grateful.
神盾局全体特工请注意
<i>Attention all S.H.I E.L.D. agents,</i>
我是史蒂夫 罗杰斯
<i>this is Steve Rogers.</i>
这几天你们听说了我不少事
<i>You've heard a lot about me over the last few days.</i>
有些人还奉命追捕我
<i>Some of you were even ordered to hunt me down.</i>
现在你们该知道真相了
But I think it's time you know the truth.
神盾局已经变了
S.H.I.E.L.D. is not what we thought it was.
他被九头蛇接管了
It's been taken over by HYDRA.
亚历山大·皮尔斯就是他们的头儿
<i>Alexander Pierce is their leader.</i>
特战队和洞察计划团队也是
<i>The S.T.R.I.K.E. and Insight crew are HYDRA as well.</i>
我不知道还有谁是
<i>I don't know how many more,</i>
但他们就在这楼里
but I know they're in the building.
可能就站在你身边
<i>They could be standing right next to you.</i>
他们就快要得逞了
<i>They almost have what they want.</i>
获得绝对掌控
<i>Absolute control.</i>
他们刺杀了尼克·弗瑞
They shot Nick Fury.
事情并没有到此结束
<i>And it won't end there.</i>
如果你们今天发射了那些天空母舰
If you launch those helicarriers today,
九头蛇就能杀掉任何阻碍他们的人
<i>HYDRA will be able to kill anyone that stands in their way.</i>
除非我们阻止他们
<i>Unless we stop them.</i>
我知道这很难
<i>I know I'm asking a lot.</i>
但自由的代价是高昂的 一向如此
<i>But the price of freedom is high. It always has been.</i>
我愿意付出这个代价
And it's a price I'm willing to pay.
如果我是唯一一个 那也没关系
And if I'm the only one, then so be it.
但我相信不会只有我一个
But I'm willing to bet I'm not.
你事先写过稿子 还是刚才临场发挥
Did you write that down first, or was it off the top of your head?
你个自以为是的混蛋
You smug son of a bitch.
逮捕他
Arrest him.
这层楼我说了算
I guess I've got the floor.
进入发射序列 把飞船送上天
Preempt the launch sequence. Send those ships up now.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
我
Um...
我说有问题吗
Is there a problem?
对不起 长官
I'm sorry, sir.
我不能发射飞船
I'm not gonna launch those ships.
是队长的命令
Captain's orders.
从位子上滚开
Move away from your station.
他说了
Like he said...
站在那别动
Hold it right there.
把枪放下
Put the gun down!
是队长的命令
Captain's orders.
你站错队了 特工
You picked the wrong side, Agent.
那要看你站在哪了
Depends on where you're standing.
关掉机库大门
Close the bay door!
马上快关掉机库大门
Close the bay door now!
关掉机库大门
Close the bay door!
他们在启动发射程序
They're initiating launch.
嘿 队长 我怎么分辨好人和坏人
Hey, Cap, how do we know the good guys from the bad guys?
朝你开枪的就是坏人
If they're shooting at you, they're bad.
队长
Hey, Cap,
我找到你说的那些坏人了
I found those bad guys you were talking about.
你没事吧
You okay?
一时半会儿死不了
I'm not dead yet.
我来问你个问题
Let me ask you a question.
要是明天恐怖分子进攻南亚
What if Pakistan marched into Mumbai tomorrow
你也知道他们会把你的女儿们
and you knew that they were going to drag your daughters
拖进足球场处决掉
into a soccer stadium for execution,
而你扳个开关就能阻止这一切
and you could just stop it, with a flick of the switch.
你会吗
Wouldn't you?
你们会吗
Wouldn't you all?
如果是你的开关就不会
Not if it was your switch.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我是不是扫了你的兴
Did I step on your moment?
卫星进入三千英尺范围
Satellites in range at 3,000 feet.
猎鹰 报告情况
Falcon, status?
打着呢
Engaging.
好了 队长 我进来了
All right, Cap. I'm in.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
还有八分钟 队长
<i>Eight minutes, Cap.</i>
在努力
Working on it.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
她在终止安全协议
She's disabling security protocols
把所有机密都发到网上
and dumping all the secrets onto the Internet.
- 包括九头蛇   - 还有神盾局的
- Including HYDRA'S.   - And S.H.I.E.L.D.'s.
如果你这么做
If you do this,
你的过去就再也藏不住了
none of your past is gonna remain hidden.
你准备好让世界看到你真实的样子了
Are you sure you're ready for the world to see you
你真实的样子了
as you really are?
那你呢
Are you?
一号锁定
Alpha lock.
猎鹰 你在哪儿
Falcon, where are you now?
我得绕点儿路
I had to take a detour.
我进来了
I'm in.
二号锁定
Bravo lock.
两个好了 还差一个
Two down, one to go.
所有飞行员立即起飞
All S.H.I.E.L.D. pilots, scramble.
我们是罗杰斯队长唯一的空中支援
We're the only air support Captain Rogers has got.
禁用加密需要有高级命令
Disabling the encryption is an executive order.
得有两名A级别成员到场
It takes two Alpha Level members.
不用担心 你的伴儿来了
Don't worry. Company's coming.
收到我的花了吗
Did you get my flowers?
- 很高兴你能来 尼克   - 是吗
- I'm glad you're here, Nick.   - Really?
不就是你把我害死的吗
Because I thought you had me killed.
这种事你懂的
You know how the game works.
为什么让我做了神盾局的头儿
So why make me head of S.H.I.E.L.D.?
因为你是我见过
Because you were the best,
最优秀最冷酷无情的人
and the most ruthless person I ever met.
我一生尽我所能保护全人民
I did what I did to protect people.
我们的敌人就是你的敌人 尼克
Our enemies are your enemies, Nick.
暴乱 战争
Disorder. War.
迟早我们最强的敌人会发射核弹
It's just a matter of time before a dirty bomb goes off in Moscow,
或者芝加哥被EMP导弹袭击
or an EMP fries Chicago.
外交
Diplomacy?
应付局面而已 权宜之计
A holding action, Nick. A band-aid.
你明白我从哪儿知道这些的吧 波哥达
And you know where I learned that. Bogota.
你没有请示我 直接做了该做的
You didn't ask. You just did what had to be done.
只需要牺牲2千万人
I can bring order to the lives of seven billion people
我就能给70亿人建立新秩序
by sacrificing 20 million.
只差最后一步了 尼克
It's the next step, Nick.
只要你有胆量执行
If you have the courage to take it.
不 我有胆量不执行
No. I have the courage not to.
启动视网膜扫描
<i>Retinal scanner active.</i>
你以为我们会傻到没从系统中清除你的权限
You don't think we've wiped your clearance from the system?
我知道你会删除我的密码
I know you erased my password.
会删掉视网膜扫描记录
Probably deleted my retinal scan.
不过你要是想玩儿过我 部长先生
But if you want to stay ahead of me, Mr Secretary,
你得把两只眼睛都睁大点儿
you need to keep both eyes open.
A级别确认
<i>Alpha level confirmed.</i>
加密代码接受
<i>Encryption code accepted.</i>
安全戒备解除
<i>Safeguards removed.</i>
航母在左舷45度方向
Charlie carrier is 45 degrees off the port bow.
还剩6分钟
Six minutes.
山姆 捎我一程
Hey, Sam, gonna need a ride.
收到 准备好了通知我
Roger. Let me know when you're ready.
已经好了
I just did!
你比你看起来重多了你知道不
You know, you're a lot heavier than you look.
早饭吃多了
I had a big breakfast.
史蒂夫
Steve!
队长 队长 请回话 你还好吗
<i>Cap! Cap, come in. Are you okay?</i>
我还好
Yeah, I'm here.
我还在天空母舰上
I'm still on the helicarrier.
- 你在哪儿   - 我在地面上
- Where are you?   <i>- I'm grounded.</i>
飞行设备损毁了 抱歉 队长
The suit's down. Sorry, Cap.
别担心 我能搞定
Don't worry. I got it.
紧急疏散警报
<i>Emergency evacuation alert.</i>
请全体人员前往指定的安全区域
<i>All personnel, proceed to designated safety zones.</i>
全体神盾局特工在第四集合点集合
All S.H.I.E.L.D. agents regroup at Rally Point Delta.
长官 理事会那边出事了
<i>Sir, the Council's been breached.</i>
- 重复   - 黑寡妇在上面
- Repeat, Dispatch.   <i>- Black Widow's up there.</i>
我上去
Headed up.
- 猎鹰   - 什么事儿
- Falcon?   <i>- Yeah.</i>
朗姆洛正赶往理事会那边
Rumlow's headed for the Council.
交给我吧
I'm on it.
会有人死的 巴基
People are gonna die, Buck.
我不能不管
I can't let that happen.
求你别逼我这么做
Please don't make me do this.
完成
Done.
一下子就火了
And it's trending.
把枪放下 如果你不想
Unless you want a two-inch hole in your sternum,
胸骨上被开个2英寸的洞
I'd put that gun down.
你把它别上去时就启动了
That was armed the moment you pinned it on.
松手
Drop it!
快松手
我在41层 往西南楼梯井过去
I'm on 41, headed toward the southwest stairwell.
别惹我
This is gonna hurt.
九头蛇从来没有罪犯 只有秩序
There are no prisoners with HYDRA. Just order.
服从总是来自棍棒之下
And order only comes through pain.
- 那你准备吃点苦头了   - 闭上你的嘴
- You ready for yours?   - Man, shut the hell up.
还需要多久 中尉
Lieutenant, how much longer?
还需要65秒与卫星连接
<i>65 seconds to satellite link.</i>
重新锁定目标 降下武器阵列
Targeting grid engaged. Lowering weapons array now.
1分钟
One minute.
30秒了 队长
<i>30 seconds, Cap.</i>
准备待命
Stand by.
3号...
Charlie...
已升至3000英尺高空
<i>We've reached 3,000 feet.</i>
卫星连接上了
Sat link coming online now.
使用算法
Deploy algorithm.
算法已使用
Algorithm deployed.
可以锁定目标了
<i>We are go to target.</i>
目标达到饱和值
<i>Target saturation reached.</i>
选定所有目标
All targets assigned.
准备好就开火
Fire when ready.
准备开火
Firing in...
三
<i>Three,</i>
二
two...
一
One.
3号锁定
Charlie lock.
攻击目标呢
Where are the targets?
目标去哪儿了
完毕 队长 赶快离开那儿
Okay, Cap, get out of there.
重新定向  以获取目标
现在开火
Fire now.
- 可是队长...   - 开火
- But, Steve...   - Do it!
立即开火
<i>Do it now!</i>
真是浪费啊
What a waste.
你还对罗杰斯成功的可能抱有疑问吗
So, you still on the fence about Rogers' chances?
该走了 女议员 这边 来吧
Time to go, Councilwoman. This way. Come on.
你得开飞机带我离开这儿
You're going to fly me out of here.
你记得吗 我曾愿意为你挡子弹
You know, there was a time I would've taken a bullet for you.
你确实挡过
You already did.
需要的时候还会再吃一颗
You will again, when it's useful.
重启 已武装
诺曼诺夫
Romanoff.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
娜塔莎 醒醒
Natasha! Come on!
扎得我真疼
Those really do sting.
九头蛇万岁
Hail HYDRA.
你根本不是我的对手
You're out of your depth, kid.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
拜托告诉我你们在那架直升机上
Please tell me you got that chopper in the air!
山姆 你在哪儿
<i>Sam, where are you?</i>
41层的西北角
41st floor! Northwest corner!
我们过来了 待在原地别动
We're on it! Stay where you are!
做不到啊
Not an option!
41楼 41
41st floor! 41st!
他们又没把楼层号码标在大楼外墙上
It's not like they put the floor numbers on the outside of the building.
希尔 史蒂夫在哪儿 你知道罗杰斯的位置吗
Hill! Where's Steve? You got a location on Rogers?
你认识我
You know me.
不 我不认识
No, I don't!
巴基
Bucky.
你从小就认识我
You've known me your whole life.
你的名字是詹姆斯·布坎南·巴恩斯
Your name is James Buchanan Barnes.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我不会和你打的
I'm not gonna fight you.
你是我的挚友
You're my friend.
你是我的任务
You're my mission.
你是 我的 任务！
You're my mission!
那就完成它吧
Then finish it.
因为我会一直陪你到最后
Because I'm with you to the end of the line.
马文·盖伊
黑手煞星
注意左边
On your left.
你是否愿意庄严宣誓 你所陈述的一切均为事实
<i>Do you solemnly swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,</i>
且句句属实
<i>and nothing but the truth?</i>
我发誓
<i>I do.</i>
为什么罗杰斯队长不能出庭作证
<i>Why haven't we yet heard from Captain Rogers?</i>
我不知道他还有什么要说的
I don't know what there is left for him to say.
因为在波托马可河里飘着的残骸已经说明了一切
I think the wreck in the middle of the Potomac
残骸已经说明了一切
made his point fairly eloquently.
他至少可以出来解释一下
Well, he could explain how
在跟你联手毁掉我们的情报机构之后
this country is expected to maintain its national security
这个国家接下来要怎么维护国家安全
now that he and you have laid waste to our intelligence apparatus.
九头蛇卖给你们的不是情报而是谎言
HYDRA was selling you lies, not intelligence.
这其中好像有不少是你自己告诉我们的
Many of which you seemed to have had a personal hand in telling.
特工 委员会中
Agent, you should know
有部分委员认为考虑到你既为这个国际服务过 也背叛过它
that there are some on this committee
你既为这个国际服务过
who feel, given your service record,
也背叛过它
both for this country and against it,
这足以判你监禁
that you belong in a penitentiary.
而不是在国会大厦大放厥词
Not mouthing off on Capitol Hill.
你们不会把我关进监狱
You're not going to put me in a prison.
你们不会把我们中的任何一员关进监狱 知道为什么吗
You're not going to put any of us in a prison. You know why?
还请明示
Do enlighten us.
因为你们不能没有我们
Because you need us.
没错 这个世界很脆弱
<i>Yes, the world is a vulnerable place,</i>
而且没错 这其中有我们的责任
<i>and yes, we help make it that way.</i>
但同时我们也是最有能力保护它的人
<i>But we're also the ones best qualified to defend it.</i>
所以如果你们想要逮捕我 那就逮捕我吧
So, if you want to arrest me, arrest me.
你们知道哪里能找到我
You'll know where to find me.
我说 你经历过这种事 比我有经验
So, you've experienced this sort of thing before.
你会习惯的
You get used to it.
尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞上校
义人之路
我们在挖九头蛇的数据资料
We've been data mining HYDRA'S files.
似乎有不少人会被拖下水啊
Looks like a lot of rats didn't go down with the ship.
我今晚就去欧洲了
I'm headed to Europe tonight.
还想来问问 你要不要跟我去
Wanted to ask if you'd come.
在这之前我还有点事要做
There's something I got to do first.
你呢 威尔森 我身边需要有你这样能力的人
How about you, Wilson? Could use a man with your abilities.
比起间谍我更愿意当个士兵
I'm more of a soldier than a spy.
那好吧
All right, then.
要是有人找我 告诉他们上这儿来找我
Anybody asks for me, tell them they can find me, right here.
你应该为此感到荣幸 他差点儿就
You should be honoured. That's about as close as he gets
说出谢谢了
to saying thank you.
不跟他一起去
Not going with him?
不
No.
- 也不留下   - 不
- Not staying here.   - Nah.
我所有的假身份都暴露了 现在得搞个新的出来
I blew all my covers. I got to go figure out a new one.
可能得花点时间
That might take a while.
我想也是
I'm counting on it.
你要我帮忙的那件事
That thing you asked for,
我请了基辅的朋友帮了点儿忙
I called in a few favours from Kiev.
那你能帮我个忙吗 打给那个护士
Will you do me a favour? Call that nurse.
她不是护士了
She's not a nurse.
你也不是神盾局特工了
And you're not a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent.
- 再问一下她叫什么来着   - 莎朗
- What was her name again?   - Sharon.
她挺不错的
She's nice.
凡事留心 史蒂夫
Be careful, Steve.
最好不要挖得太深
You might not want to pull on that thread.
你现在是要去找他
You're going after him.
你不必跟我一起
You don't have to come with me.
我知道
I know.
什么时候行动
When do we start?
结束了 弗瑞把一切都公之于众了
It's over. Fury has released everything to the public.
是他知道的一切
Everything he knows about.
西崔克尔男爵 如果他们得到我们藏匿在这的一点消息
<i>Herr</i> Strucker, if they get word of our work here,
如果他们发现我们效力于九头蛇
if they find out we serve HYDRA...
九头蛇 神盾局
HYDRA, S.H.I.E.L.D.
一枚硬币的两面 已经大势所去了
Two sides of a coin that's no longer currency.
我们手上的
What we have
比他们所知道的 更有价值
is worth more than any of them ever knew.
我们只是触及一点儿毛皮就已经
We've only scratched the surface and already,
我们把全世界其他为九头蛇效力的机构丢给
there are other facilities doing HYDRA'S good work around the world.
美国队长和他那帮五颜六色的朋友
We'll feed them to Captain America and his colourful friends,
引开他们的注意力
and keep them off our scent.
那志愿者呢
What about the volunteers?
死掉的将会被深埋在地下
The dead will be buried so deep
连他们的魂魄也找不到
their own ghosts won't be able to find them.
那幸存下来的呢
And the survivors?
就像这对双胞胎
The twins.
指快银和绯红女巫
他们迟早要见到这对双胞胎
Sooner or later, they will meet the twins.
这再也不是间谍的天下
It's not a world of spies any more.
甚至不是一个英雄的世界
Not even a world of heroes.
这是一个奇迹的时代 博士
This is the age of miracles, Doctor.
没有什么比一个奇迹更让人
There's nothing more horrifying
毛骨悚然的了
than a miracle.
本字幕由 MARVELATORS漫威行动组 原创出品
仅供交流学习 请勿用于商业用途